Turkus, Burton B. Arbitration Files 5712
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Trans-World Airlines System Board of Adjustment vs. Linda Ellis, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  5/22/78. Issue: Discipline - discharge - absences - tardiness. Includes: Exhibits, correspondence, briefs, Arbitrator's notes.
- Trans-World Airlines System Board of Adjustment vs. Kenneth W. Hunter., 1976 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  6/23/76. Issue: Discipline - discharge - absences. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, correspondence, briefs, exhibits.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. Transport Workers Union, Local 551, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  11/12/76. Issue: Scheduling. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, correspondence, briefs, exhibits.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. IAM, Lodge 142 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  Not dated. Includes: Correspondence, briefs. No Award.
- Trans-World Airlines System Board of Adjustment vs. Linda Costa, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  3/17/80. Issue: Discipline - discharge - tardiness. Includes: No Award.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. Transport Workers Union, Local 551, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  6/28/76. Issue: cancelled.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. Independent Federation of Flight Attendants, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  1/19/78. Issue: Discipline - discharge - misconduct. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, correspondence, briefs, exhibits.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. Independent Federation of Flight Attendants, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  3/21/78. Issue: Discipline - failure to attend Company meetings. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, correspondence, briefs, exhibits
- Trans-World Airlines vs. IAM, District 142, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  8/19/71. Issue: Absences - discipline. Includes: Award only.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. IAM, District 142, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  11/1/71. Issue: Discipline - discharge. Includes: Award only.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. IAM, District 142, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  4/20/73. Issue: Discipline - discharge. Includes: Award only.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. International Airline Pilots Association, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  6/7/71. Issue: Discipline - off-duty conduct. Issue: Award and opinion only
- Trans-World Airlines vs. Transport Workers Union, Airline Stewards and Stewardesses Association, Local 550, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  11/19/71. Issue: Discipline - discharge. Includes: Award only.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. IAM, District 142, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  11/1/72. Issue: Discipline - discharge. Includes: Award only.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. Transport Workers Union, Local 551, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  3/4/75. Issue: Discipline - discharge - improper job attitude -customer relations. Includes: Award only.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. Airline Pilots Association, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 38)
  9/2/75. Issue: Reinstatement - following illness or physical disability. Includes: Award only.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. Transport Workers Union, Local 551, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  12/9/74. Issue: Discipline - discharge - violation of plant rules. Includes: Award only.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. Christine Eidenschink, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 40)
  6/25/73. Issue: Discipline - discharge - improper job conduct - customer relations. Includes: Award only.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. Alice Blick, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  8/14/73. Issue: Absences - excessive excused absences. Includes: Award only.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. Airline Pilots Association, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 42)
  9/3/75. Issue: Vacation pay - layoff. Includes: Award only.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. Airline Pilots Association, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 43)
  4/28/75. Issue: Schedules of work - rest breaks. Includes: Award only.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. Independent Federation of Flight Attendants, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 44)
  4/20/78. Issue: settled.
- Trans-World Airlines vs. IAM, District 142, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 45)
  9/5/72. Issue: Discipline - discharge. Includes: Opinion and award only.
- Tri-Wall Containers, Inc. vs. International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulfite and Papermill Workers, Wassaic Local 867, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 46)
  2/28/73. Issue: Discipline - violation of plant rules. Includes: Award only.
- Triborough Bridge and Tunnel Authority vs. AFSCME, District Council 37, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 47)
  4/11/80. Issue: Arbitrability - jurisdiction; vacancies - method of filling. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, briefs, supporting documentation.
- Triborough Bridge and Tunnel Authority vs. AFSCME, District Council 37, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 48)
  8/11/78. Issue: withdrawn.
- Triple-A Maintenance Corporation vs. SEIU, Division 100, Local 144 (Box 22, Folder 49)
  Not dated. Issue: cancelled.
- Union Beer Distributor vs. OPEIU, Local 153, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  8/31/79. Issue: Discipline - unauthorized use of Company property. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, correspondence, supporting documentation, briefs.
- Union Carbide Corporation, Linde Division, Institute, West Virginia, vs. IBT, Chauffeurs, Teamsters and Helpers Local Union 175, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  3/20/79. Issue: Absences - discipline. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, correspondence, briefs, supporting documentation, Agreement, exhibits.
- Union Carbide Corporation, Linde Division, Piscataway, New Jersey, vs. USA, Local 6789, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  11/23/79. Issue: Absences - tardiness - suspension. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, briefs, correspondence, Agreement, exhibits, supporting documentation.
- Union Labor Life Insurance Company vs. OPEIU, Local 153, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  4/18/75. Issue: Absences - excessive. Includes: Award only.
- Union Labor Life Insurance Company vs. OPEIU, Local 153, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  5/24/71. Issue: Quits - discharge versus. Includes: No Award.
- Union Labor Life Insurance Company vs. OPEIU, Local 153 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  Not dated. Issue: Insubordination - discipline. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, exhibits, supporting documentation, Agreement, correspondence. No Award.
- Union Labor Life Insurance Company vs. OPEIU, Local 153, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  5/19/78. Issue: withdrawn.
- Union Labor Life Insurance Company vs. OPEIU, Local 153, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  2/23/76. Issue: Contracts - omitted provision. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, briefs, supporting documentation.
- Union Labor Life Insurance Company vs. OPEIU, Local 153, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  4/12/76. Issue: Severance pay - plant removal. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, correspondence, briefs, Agreement
- Union Labor Life Insurance Company vs. OPEIU, Local 153, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  5/4/78. Issue: Sick leave and sick pay - doctor's certificate. Includes: Agreement, briefs, correspondence, Arbitrator's notes, supporting documentation.
- United Aircraft Corporation vs. IAMAW, Seminole Lodge 971, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  3/7/74. Issue: Overtime - discrimination. Includes: Award only.
- United Airlines, Inc. vs. IAMAW, District 141, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  8/27/71. Issue: Discipline - unauthorized use of Company property. Includes: Award only.
- United Illuminating Company vs. Utility Workers Union of America, Local 470-471, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  7/5/78 (4 separate cases.) Issue: Discipline - discharge. Includes: Agreement, Arbitrator's notes, correspondence, briefs.
- United Parcel Service, Inc. vs. IBT, General Drivers, Warehousemen, and Helpers, Local 89, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  7/30/66. Issue: Discipline - discharge. Includes: Award only.
- United Parcel Service, Inc. vs. IBT, Local 804, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  8/31/70. Issue: Discipline - discharge - fights and altercations - assault on supervisor. Includes: Award only.
- United Parcel Service, Inc. vs. IBT, Local 177, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  5/28/80. Issue: Discipline - discharge. Includes: Agreement, Arbitrator's notes, briefs, exhibits.
- United Parcel Service, Inc. vs. IAM, District 15, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  9/20/77. Issue: Discipline - discharge - overtime refusal. Includes: Agreement, briefs, exhibits, Arbitrator's notes, correspondence.
- United Press International vs. Newspaper Guild, Wire Service Guild, Local 222, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  10/18/77. Issue: Probationary employees - arbitrability. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, briefs, correspondence.
- United Services, Inc. vs. ITPE-NMU Welfare Plan, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  2/21/79. Issue: Welfare Funds - Employer's contributions. Includes: Supporting documentation, correspondence, legal documents.
- United Technologies Corporation vs. IBT, Local 1150, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  7/10/80. Issue: Discipline - discharge - violation of plant rules. Includes: Agreement, briefs, correspondence, supporting documentation, exhibits.
- United Technologies Corporation vs. IBT, Local 1150, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  12/22/82. Includes: Agreement, Arbitrator's notes, correspondence, briefs. No Award.
- U.S. Lines, Inc. vs. National Maritime Union of America, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  7/16/79. Issue: Alcoholism, drinking and intoxication - evidence. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, correspondence.
- Valley Gourmet, Ltd. vs. 1115 Joint Board, 1115 Culinary Employees Union., 1981 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  1/9/81. Issue: Certification election. Includes: Correspondence, briefs.
- Vizcaya Restaurant, Inc. vs. Hotel, Motel, Restaurant, High-Rise, and Bartenders Union, Local 355, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  7/28/75. Issue: Layoffs - super seniority. Includes: Agreement, briefs, Arbitrator's notes.
- Wagner College vs. American Association of University Professors, Wagner College Chapter, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  5/23/80. Issue: Arbitrability - timeliness; Rates of pay - increase. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, correspondence, briefs, exhibits
- Waldbaum, Inc. vs. Retail, Wholesale and Chain Store Food Employees Union, Local 338, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  11/15/82. Issue: Discipline - discharge - discrimination. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, correspondence.
- Waldbaum, Inc. vs. RWDSU, Local 338, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  11/18/82. Issue: Rates of pay - premium pay. Settled. Includes: Agreement, correspondence, briefs. No Award.
- Walgreen Eastern Company, Inc. vs. Hotel, Restaurant, and Club Employees and Bartenders Union, Local 6, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  11/22/82. Issue: Discipline - discharge. Includes: Agreement, Arbitrator's notes, correspondence.
- Wells Fargo Armored Service Corporation vs. IBT, Armored Car Division, Local 807, 1979-1980 (Box 24, Folder 5-6)
  11/6/79, 11/20/80. Issue: Classification of jobs - downgrading. Includes: Agreement, Arbitrator's notes, correspondence, briefs, exhibits.
- West Ridge Properties, Inc. vs. Hotel, Restaurant, and Club Employees and Bartenders Union, Local 6 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  Not dated. Issue: Discipline - discharge. Includes: Correspondence. No Award.
- Western Electric, Inc. vs. IBEW, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  6/29/76. Issue: Discipline - discharge - gambling on Company premises. Includes: Correspondence, briefs, supporting documentation.
- Western Electric vs. CWA, Local 1095, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  3/30/78. Issue: settled. Includes: Correspondence, briefs.
- Western Union International, Inc. vs. American Communications Association, IBT, Local 111, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  2/16/78. Issue: Discipline - suspension. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, briefs, correspondence.
- Wetvil Gourmet, Ltd. vs. Culinary Employees Union, 1115 Joint Board, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  3/10/80. Issue: Certification (election). Includes: Correspondence
- White Westinghouse Consumer Service Company vs. IBT, Local 804, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  2/14/78. Issue: Discipline - discharge. Includes: Correspondence, exhibits, briefs.
- Winged Foot Golf Club vs. Hotel, Restaurant, and Club Employees and Bartenders Union, Local 69, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  3/14/78. Issue: Discipline - breach of no- strike clause. Includes: Agreement, Arbitrator's notes, correspondence, briefs, exhibits.
- Winged Foot Golf Club vs. SEIU, Local 32E (Box 24, Folder 14)
  Issue: cancelled. Includes: Correspondence, briefs. No Award.
- WNET vs. IBEW, Local 1212, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  3/20/81. Issue: Assignment of jobs - assignment of work outside unit. Includes: Correspondence, briefs.
- Workmen's Benefit Fund of the USA vs. OPEIU, Local 153, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  8/21/75. Issue: Rates of pay - increases.
- WQXR vs. IBEW, Radio and Television Broadcast Engineers, Local 1212, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  4/6/77. Issue: Schedules of work - time-off schedules. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, briefs, correspondence, exhibits.
- Wursteria, Inc. vs. HRCEBU, Local 6, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  8/21/81. Issue: settled. Includes: No Award.
- WVNJ vs. IBEW, Local 1212, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  9/6/77. Issue: cancelled. Includes: Correspondence, briefs. No Award.
- WWHT vs. IBEW, Local 1212, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  8/3/81. Issue: cancelled. Includes: Correspondence, briefs. No Award.
- Wyckoff Heights Hospital vs. Hotel, Hospital, Nursing Home and Allied Services Union, SEIU, Local 144, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  1/17/78. Issue: Discipline - discharge - negligence and carelessness. Includes: Agreement, correspondence, briefs, exhibits.
- Wyckoff Heights Hospital vs. Hotel, Hospital, Nursing Home and Allied Services Union, SEIU, Local 144, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  5/13/82. Issue: withdrawn. Includes: Correspondence, briefs.
- Yellow Fingers Restaurant vs. HRCEBU, Local 6, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  5/29/81. Issue: Discipline - discharge - theft - pilfering. Includes: Arbitrator's notes, supporting documentation, briefs, exhibits.
- Various arbitration cases bound by subject and Arbitration-reference documents (Box 25, Folder All)
  Discharge cases, Suspension and discipline cases, Miscellaneous items. Articles, Pamphlets, Memos, Newsletters, Forms, Other Arbitrators' decisions.
- Other professional papers (Box 26, Folder All)
  Correspondence, Legal documents regarding non-arbitration legal cases, Seminar and conference material, Office bills, Miscellaneous items.
- American Airlines Dispute, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  Includes letter of appointment from President JFK
- Biographical Data, Burton B. Turkus (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1957-1967 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  Congratulatory letters on Turkus's appointment as impartial arbitrator of water front labor disputes between shippers and Longshoremen. Other correspondence on various appointments
- Arbitration-related news clippings (Box 27, Folder 4)
  1950s
- Criminal Syndicate Rules Gambling Operations, 1953 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  (Draft for UAW-CIO educational booklet on organized in-plant gambling.) June 29, 1953
- Copies of Correspondence from Burton Turkus, 1958-1961 (Box 27, Folder 6)
- Newsletters, bulletins on arbitration (Box 27, Folder 7)
- Newspaper clippings, 1957-1966 (Box 27, Folder 8)
- Newspaper clippings, 1957-1966 (Box 27, Folder 9)
- B. Turkus letter to the editor, NJ Labor Editor, other miscellaneous news clippings, 1947-1971 (Box 27, Folder 10)